So today we're honored to swear in
Janine Piro, somebody I've known for a
long time and she's an incredible person
and incredible woman as our new interim
United States Attorney for the District
of Colombia. That's a big deal. And I'd
like to congratulate Janine and her
whole family. And we have Christine with
us and Alex I know is uh in a very very
important place right now. And uh the
two children but they're not children
anymore. And I've heard that uh
Christine, you're doing unbelievably
well and very successful at a great law
firm. So, it's great to have you with
us. Thank you very much. Over five
decades, Janine Piro, known by millions
as Judge Janine, has devoted her life to
the pursuit of justice, the defense of
freedom, and the fair, equal, and
impartial rule of law. And that's what
she's about. She was a great DA. I
remember very well. She was as good as
anybody I've seen. She began a career in
1975 as an assistant district attorney
in Westchester County, New York, where
she prosecuted violent crimes. And that
was a serious prosecutor. And she went
after real criminals, not uh not fake
criminals like we seem to do today