So today we're honored to swear in
Janine Piro, somebody I've known for a
long time and she's an incredible person
and incredible woman as our new interim
United States Attorney for the District
of Colombia. That's a big deal. And I'd
like to congratulate Janine and her
whole family. And we have Christine with
us and Alex I know is uh in a very very
important place right now. And uh the
two children but they're not children
anymore. And I've heard that uh
Christine, you're doing unbelievably
well and very successful at a great law
firm. So, it's great to have you with
us. Thank you very much. Over five
decades, Janine Piro, known by millions
as Judge Janine, has devoted her life to
the pursuit of justice, the defense of
freedom, and the fair, equal, and
impartial rule of law. And that's what
she's about. She was a great DA. I
remember very well. She was as good as
anybody I've seen. She began a career in
1975 as an assistant district attorney
in Westchester County, New York, where
she prosecuted violent crimes. And that
was a serious prosecutor. And she went
after real criminals, not uh not fake
criminals like we seem to do today
nowadays, people that shouldn't be
prosecuted, including rape, murder, and
was tireless warrior. a tireless warrior
on behalf of the most vulnerable people
in our society. In that role, Janine
helped create one of our country's first
domestic violence bureaus. I think it
was the first Janine. And as its chief,
she revolutionized victim protection and
bold innovative policies like very few
people even thought of. In 1990, Janine
became the first female judge in
Westchester County history. And
following the year and by the way very
distinguished had an unbelievable
distinguished career. And in the
following years she presided over
numerous complex criminal cases. The
reason they were complex is that other
judges were not able to understand them.
They were called the complex cases. My
sister had them too. They always used to
give her the complex cases because other
people didn't understand them. Including
highstakes felony narcotics trials. Her
outstanding judicial record earned her
the honor of being named the number one
judge in 1990 by the Independent Fund
for Modern Courts. That's nationwide.
Outstanding judge. The following year,
Judge Janine was elected Westchester
County District Attorney. Became the top
prosecutor for a jurisdiction that
included some of the largest suburbs in
New York City, including Yoners and
White Plains. It's a big deal. As
district attorney, Janine tackled
high-profile violent crime cases and
established one of the nation's most
successful cyber crime units to combat
online child abuse. She was way ahead of
a lot of people. They still aren't
there. If you get right down, I mean,
from what I hear, they're still not
there in many cases back there where we
come from. In addition to her stellar
legal career, Janine also excelled in
news media as her as you know and she's
become one of the most beloved political
figures through uh her time on
television because she's been very very
successful at thing called television.
She got out of uh what she was doing and
frankly she does them both great but
she's really to me she'll always be
known as a great lawyer and a great
prosecutor which is what she's doing
now. So Janine Piro I have no doubt will
be an exceptional US attorney for the
District of Columbia. One of the truly
most important positions in our country
of any position where she will restore
public safety in our nation's capital,
break up vicious street gangs and
criminal networks and ensure equal
justice under the law. You'll see very
very big improvements in the DC area.
That I can promise you. So I want to
congratulate Janine. I want to
congratulate you and Christine and your
whole family. on this uh undertaking and
as you know Pam Bondi is doing an
unbelievable job uh is our real leader
leader in the fight against crime and
Pam heard about this and Pam said I'll
have to find time for Janine she doesn't
have time to do this but for Janine she
did and she's going to be doing the
swearing in so Pam thank you very much
for the great job you're doing and for
swearing in our friend Justice Janine
good thank you come on
I do solemnly swear I Jine do solemnly
swear that I will support and defend the
Constitution of the United States that I
will support and defend the Constitution
of the United States against all enemies
foreign foreign and domestic. against
all enemies, foreign and domestic. And
that I will bear true faith and
allegiance to the same. And that I will
bear true faith and allegiance to the
same. And that I take this obligation
freely. And that I take this obligation
freely without any mental reservation
without any mental reservation or
purpose of evasion or purpose of
evasion. and I will well and faithfully
and that I will well and faithfully
discharge the duties discharge the
duties of the office upon which I am
about to enter of the office upon which
I am about to enter. So help me God. So
help me God. Congratulations. Thank you.
[Applause]
Thank you, Mr. president and thank you
madam attorney general uh both my
friends for many
years long ago I went to law school to
study about justice and to bring justice
to victims of violent crimes women and
the elderly I fought to give them a
voice in a system that was both blind
and deaf to their
concerns I dedicated my heart and soul
to making sure that there was a system
that responded to them. My profile and
my prosecutorial successes garnered
public attention and my life took
unexpected t turns. Through all of this,
President Trump, you have remained as
steadfast as one of my earliest
supporters and champions. You never
wavered. You were always steadfast,
trustworthy, and confident.
Today, Mr. President, you bring me back
to my
roots. And it is a larger arena, but no
less an arena where we need justice,
where we need to send a message that
justice will be honored in the District
of Colombia.
And just last week here in our nation's
capital, two people on the brink of
beginning their life had hopes and
dreams that were never realized because
a coldblooded murderer made a decision
to shoot them down on the streets on a
cold, rainy night in our nation's
capital. This will not go without just
accounting.
My voice should be heard loud and
clear. No more. No more tolerance of
hatred. No more mercy for criminals.
Violence will be addressed directly with
the appropriate punishment.
And this city will again become a
shining city on a hill in an America
that President Trump has promised to
make great again and will make safe
again. Mr. President, America thanks you
and I thank you.
Any
questions? Any questions?
Anything for you? You just want to talk
to him. I get it.
Thank you. She's going to be fantastic.
Thank you very much. They really all
there's no question because there's no
doubt. We have no doubt you're going to
be fantastic. Thank you, Mr. President.
Mr. President, Mr. President. Mr.
President. Yeah, Mr. President. Russia.
Mr. President, please. Um,
do you believe the Russians are being
disrespectful when they say that your
criticisms of Putin are simply an
emotional response? And do you still
believe that Putin actually wants to end
the war? I can't tell you that, but I'll
let you know in about two weeks. Within
two weeks, we're going to find out very
soon. Uh, we're going to find out
whether or not he's tapping us along or
not. And if he is, we'll respond a
little bit differently. But it'll take
about a week and a half, two weeks. We
have Mr. Mr. Witkoff is here is doing a
phenomenal job is uh dealing with them
very strongly right now. They they seem
to want to do something but until the
document is signed I can't tell you
nobody can I I can say this I can say
this that
uh I'm very disappointed at what
happened couple of nights now where
people were killed in the middle of what
you would call a negotiation. I'm very
disappointed by that. Very very
disappointed. Yeah. Please,
you've called for an end to the Ganda
war. Given the growing humanitarian
crisis and the decision of Prime
Minister Netanyahu to extend the
military operation, do you have any
frustration with his handling of the
situation of the war? No, we're dealing
with the whole situation in Gaza. We're
getting food to the people of Gaza. It's
a it's been a very nasty situation, very
nasty fight. October 7th was a very
nasty day, the worst that I think I've
ever seen. It was a horrible day and
people aren't going to forget that
either. So, we'll see how that all works
out. And Steve, would you want to say a
couple of words about Gaza because you
just have some information? Uh Steve
Woodco, do you want to come up for a
second? You might give them a little bit
of information as to what's happening
with Gaza and also Israel. We're having
some very good talks with Iran. We'll
find out whether that means anything,
but we're having good talks.
Congratulations. Well, m uh hi
everybody. I think we um uh I think that
we are on the precipice of sending out a
uh new term sheet um that hopefully will
be delivered later on today. The
president is going to review it. And I
have some very good feelings about
getting to a uh long-term resolution,
temporary cease uh temporary ceasefire
and a long-term resolution, a peaceful
resolution of that conflict. Mr.
President, you said having to do with
Iran. We're having very good talks with
Mr. President, you said yesterday that
Putin is playing with fire. What would
be the consequences for Russia if he
continues to if Russia continues? Well,
I'm not going to tell you exactly, but
uh the words speak pretty loud. Uh we're
not we're not happy about that
situation. I think we're uh we're doing
very well with Iran. I think we're doing
very well with
Gaza, but we are doing very well with
Iran. And I think we're going to see
some some uh something very sensible
because there are only two outcomes. You
know what the two outcomes? There's a a
smart outcome and there's a violent
outcome. and and I don't think anybody
wants to see the second, but I think
we're uh we've made a lot of progress
and we'll see. You know, they still have
to uh agree to the final stages of a
document, but I think you could be very
well surprised what happens there and
it'll be a great thing for them. They
could have a great country into the
future. Yeah. Mr. President, Elon Musk
in a television interview criticized the
one be big beautiful bill saying he was
disappointed it it didn't cut enough
essentially that undercut the Doge
efforts. What's your reaction to that?
Well, my reaction is a lot of things.
Number one, we have to get a lot of
votes. We can't be uh cutting, you know,
we need we need to get a lot of support
and we have a lot of support. We had to
get it through the House. The House was
uh we have no Democrats. You know, if
it's up to the Democrats, they'll take
the 65% increase. You know, if that
doesn't get approved, this country is
going to have a 65% increase in taxes
and lots of other problems, big
problems, almost bigger than that.
But we'll have a 65% increase as opposed
to the largest tax cut in the history of
our country. Uh we will be negotiating
that bill and uh I'm not happy about
certain aspects of it, but I'm thrilled
by other aspects of it. That's the way
they go. It's very big. It's the big
beautiful bill. But the beautiful is
because of all of the things we have. Uh
the biggest thing being I would say the
uh uh the level of tax cutting that
we're going to be doing. We're going to
make people really be able to We'll have
one of the We'll have the lowest tax
rate we've ever had in the history of
our country and tremendous amounts of
benefit are going to the middle inome
people of our country. Low and middle
income people of of our country. So,
we're going to see what happens because
the Senate, as you know, is negotiating
with us and they have to then go back to
the House and, you know, it's got a way
to go. But, uh, I I have to say Speaker
Johnson and Thun have done an incredible
job. John Thun has done a fant leader
Thun uh a fantastic job and they're
working together with me and others and
I think we have an amazing if we pull
this off remember we have zero Democrat
votes because they're bad people there's
something wrong with them you know
they're they'll let people pour into our
country single biggest problem is we had
21 million people pour into our country
probably higher than that and they're
people that weren't supposed to be here
and many of those people are bad
murderers drug dealers, the mentally
insane. They were closing mental
institutions all over the world. Not
South America, all over the world.
They're coming into our country and
we're getting them out. We're having a
hard time because some judges aren't
making it very easy for us. And it's
tough enough. They approve that. They
allow that to happen to our country. We
don't have one Democrat vote. And if I
were a Democrat, I'd be voting for this
bill and I'd get elected to any position
I want as a Democrat. They're crazy.
They're voting for a 65% tax increase
and they're only doing it for hatred.
They're not doing it for any reason.
They know it's terrible, terrible
politics in my opinion. But so we have
no Democrat votes. That means we have to
get almost all Republican votes. And I
think we're very close to doing that. I
think it'll be very successful. Yeah,
please. Mr. President, Wall Street
analysts have coined a new term called
the taco trade. They're saying Trump
always chickens out under tariff threats
and that's why markets are higher this
week. What's your response to that? I
kick out. Chicken out. Oh, isn't that
nice chicken out? I've never heard that.
You mean because I reduced China from
145% that I set down to 100 and then
down to another number and I said you
have to open up your whole country and
because uh I I gave the European Union a
50% tax uh tariff and they called up and
they said, "Please, let's meet right
now. Please let's meet right now." And I
said, 'Okay, I'll give you till Janine.
I actually asked them. I said, 'What's
the date? Because they weren't willing
to meet. And after I did what I did,
they said, "We'll meet anytime you
want." And we have an end date of July
9th. You call that chickening out?
Because we have 14 trillion dollars now
invested, committed to investing when
Biden didn't have practically anything.
Biden, this country was dying. You know,
we have the hottest country anywhere in
the world. I went to Saudi Arabia. The
king told me, he said, "You got the
hottest c. We have the hottest country
in the world right now. Six months ago,
this country was stone cold dead. We had
a dead country. We had a country people
didn't think it was going to survive."
And you ask a nasty question like that.
Uh it's called negotiation. And you set
a number and if you go down, you know,
if I set a number at a ridiculous high
number and I go down a little bit, you
know, a little bit, they want me to hold
that number, 145% tariff. Even I said,
man, that really got up. You know how it
got? Because of fentinol and many other
things and you added it up. I said,
where are we now? We're at 145%. I said,
woo, that's high. That's high. They were
doing no business whatsoever. And they
were having a lot of problems. We were
very nice to China. I don't know if
they're going to be nice to us, but we
were very nice to China. And in many
ways, I think we really helped China
tremendously because, you know, they
were having great difficulty because we
were basically going cold turkey with
China. We were doing no business because
of the tariff because it was so high.
But I knew that. But don't ever say what
you said. That's a nasty question. Go
ahead. To me, that's the nastiest
question. Wait a minute. Wait, wait. Go
ahead, please. President Zilinski says
he's ready to sit down with you and
Vladimir Putin in Geneva and it sounds
like General Kellogg is working on
preparations for that. Are you planning
to sit down with the two of them? Well,
I will if it's necessary. You know,
takes uh we have to uh I think I'm at
this point. I wish it would have been
that way a couple of months ago, but at
this point we're working on President
Putin and we'll see where we are. I
think we're doing fine, but we'll see. I
don't like what's happening. That's one
thing I'll say I don't like. When I see
rockets being shot into cities, that's
no good. We're not going to allow it.
You've always said that the war never
would have started if you were would
have never happened and it didn't. He
doesn't seem willing to do anything that
you want him to do. Do you still believe
that that he wouldn't have launched a
war? No. No. We would have never had a
war. We would have never had a war. If I
were president, if the election weren't
rigged, you wouldn't have had the war.
You wouldn't had the war. You wouldn't
had inflation. uh you wouldn't have had
October 7th. That would have never
happened because Iran was stone cold
broke. They didn't have any money to
give to Hamas or Hezbollah. You wouldn't
have had that Afghanistan most
embarrassing moment in the history of
our country. You wouldn't have had any
of it. You wouldn't have had inflation
because energy costs. Look what
happened. I brought inflation down to
practically zero. And all of the
groceries and all of the eggs and all of
the things that you've been hearing
about, they're back down. They're way
down from where they were. I did
something in four months that nobody's
seen. And I have to say in four months,
and I said it before, and everyone's
talking about it all over the world.
We've got the hottest country anywhere
in the world right now. We're the only
country anybody's even talking about.
All right. Please go ahead. What stops
you from imposing new sanctions on
Russia? Uh, only the fact that if I
think I'm close to getting a deal, I
don't want to screw it up by doing that.
Let me tell you, I'm a lot tougher than
the people you're talking about. But uh
you have to know when to use that if I
think it's going to hurt a deal. This
isn't my war. This is Biden's war,
Zalinsk's war, and Putin's war. This
isn't Trump's war. I'm only here for one
thing, to see if I can end it to save
5,000 lives a week and a lot of money.
The money being much less important
because I made that money. I went to
Saudi Arabia, Qatar, and UAE, and we
brought back $5.1 trillion.
So, I made that money in about two
hours, the money that we're talking
about. But it's still three, think of
it, $300 billion we've spent with no
checks, no balances. They just send
cash. You can imagine what's happened to
that money. I never saw anything like it
in my life. But I'm more interested
because I picked up 5.1 trillion. And by
the way, got a beautiful big magnificent
free airplane for the United States Air
Force. Okay. Very proud of that, too.
They tried to say, "Oh, it's Trump's
airplane." Oh, yeah. Sure. It's too big.
It's frankly, it's it's too big. Much
too big. When do we expect that to be
the Air Force One? Well, it's here
already. Yeah, it's in the country. It's
being refitted for military standard.
How much will it cost to refit it? Oh, I
don't know. Whatever it is, a lot a hell
of a lot less than building a new one.
We're waiting too long from Boeing.
Boeing has got to get its act together.
Yeah. Sir, on Steel, this arrangement
that was just announced share. Is that
an arrangement you would consider for
Tik Tok as well?
Nothing to do with Tik Tok. Totally
different kind of a deal. We'll have to
get, you know, to do it properly, we'll
probably have to get China's approval.
China's never easy. China's never easy.
But I think, yeah, I think we'll be able
to save Tik Tok. I'd like to save Tik
Tok. I mean, Tik Tok was very good to
me. I won the young people by
37%. No Republicans ever won. And I won
by
37%. And Charlie Kirk will tell you Tik
Tok helped. But Charlie Kirk helped
also. Oh. Oh, he just happens to be
here. Look at him. He loves that we
mentioned that name, right, Charlie?
He's done great. And I appreciate all
the help. But with young people, we won
by 37%, Charlie. And you helped. But Tik
Tok was amazing. And he was the first
one. He said, "Get on TikTok." So I have
a little bit of a warm spot. I know I
shouldn't. They'll say quid proquo.
quid. Put him in jail for the rest of
his life. Quidd proquo. No, Tik Tok was
very good to me. I won young people. I
don't know if it was because of tick
tock, but it was uh it was something
happened. No Republican has ever won the
they call them young people. Young
people, you can define it a lot of
different ways, but I won every age
group in young people and it never
happened. And won by 37%. That's a lot.
Yeah. Back on back on Iran. Did you warn
uh Prime Minister Netanyahu against
taking some sort of actions that could
disrupt the talks there in a phone call
last week? Well, I'd like to be honest.
Yes, I did. Next question, please.
I did. Yeah. Senate Republicans want to
put It's not a warning. I said I don't
think it's appropriate. What What
exactly did you tell him? Did you said I
don't think it's appropriate. We're talk
we're having very good discussions with
him and I said I don't think it's
appropriate right now because if we can
settle it with a very strong document
very strong with inspections and no
trust. I don't trust anybody. I don't
trust anybody. So no trust. I want it
very strong where we can go in with
inspectors. We can take whatever we
want. We can blow up whatever we want
but nobody getting killed. We can blow
up a lab, but nobody's going to be in
the lab as opposed to everybody being in
the lab and blowing it up, right? Two
ways of doing it. Um, yeah, I told him
this would be inappropriate to do right
now because we're very close to a
solution. Now, that could change at any
moment. Could change with a phone call,
but right now I think they want to make
a deal. And uh, if we can make a deal, I
save a lot of lives.
When do you think a deal could happen on
Iran? When? on which a deal with Iran
could happen. When Oh, I don't know. I
think over the next couple of weeks if
it happens. Yeah. On the um when could
the the administration resume the
interviews for foreign students visa?
When do you think your administration
could resume these interviews for on
what? For the foreign student visa.
Yesterday there was for the French
visas. For the foreign all the foreign
students. Oh, for the foreign visas.
What are you referring foreign visas
for? What are you talking about? for
colleges. College. Okay. So, you're off
of Israel. Now you're talking about
colleges, right? Okay. Uh well, we're
going to see. Look, Harvard has been a
disaster. Uh they've taken five plus, by
the way. Five billion dollars plus. Five
billion. Nobody knew that they were
making this kind. If we didn't do this,
nobody would have we would have never
found this out. Pam, they're taking5
billion dollar. And I'd rather see that
money go to trade schools. And by the
way, they're totally anti-Semitic at
Harvard, as you know, and some other
colleges, too, in all fairness to them.
And uh it's been exposed, very exposed.
And I think they're dealing very badly.
Every time they fight, they lose another
$250 million. Yesterday we found another
hundred million. And they have, you
know, they have a fund 52 an endowment,
52 billion dollars. All right. They got
a lot of that from the United States.
And I think it's ridiculous. I think
this uh
everyone's coming up to me saying, "We
love the idea of trade schools." With
that kind of money and money from
others, but money from them, you can
have the best trade schools anywhere in
the world. You give them to Iowa,
Indiana, lots of good states, well-run
states, and you give them the money.
They can only be used for trade schools.
And they'll teach people how to build
motors and cars and AI. you know, the
AI, we're building plants. We're
building uh hundreds of billions of
dollars worth of AI plants already
started, many of them. We've never had a
boom like we're having now. You're going
to see it. Uh there's never been
anything like it. So, we're up to about
14 trillion dollars in investments.
There's never been anything even close.
You look at Biden, this guy, they had
people leaving as opposed to investing.
And they're doing it because of November
really November 5th and they're doing it
because of the tariffs. The tariffs have
been uh tremendous uh well I I can
promise you and I have great respect for
the people at the European Union. They
wouldn't be over here today
negotiating if I didn't put a 50% tariff
on. The sad thing is now when I make a
deal with them it's something much more
reasonable. They'll say, "Oh, he was
chicken. He was chicken.
That's so unbelievable.
I usually have the opposite problem.
They say you're too tough. Mr.
President, on Harvard, there were some
Jew Jewish students protesting on campus
yesterday. They said they don't want you
making these huge cuts, cutting off uh
student visas to Harvard in their name
because Harvard has to show us a target.
Okay. Harvard has to show us their
lists. They have foreign students. about
31% of their students are foreignbased,
almost
31%. We want to know where those
students come. Are they troublemakers?
What countries do they come? And we're
not going to if somebody is coming from
a certain country and they're 100% fine,
which I hope most of them are, but many
of them won't be. You're going to see
some very radical people. They're taking
people from areas of the world that are
very radicalized, and we don't want them
making trouble in our country. So, uh, I
saw yesterday that in the middle in the
middle of, uh, the UK, there was a nice
young man. He wants to go back to school
at Harvard and he looked good to me, but
I want to check his past. But we want to
be able to see why, you know, these
countries aren't helping us. They're not
investing in Harvard and all of our we
are. So, why would 31% why would a
number so big? I think number one, I
think they should have a cap of maybe
around 15%.
not 31%. We have people want to go to
Harvard and other schools. They can't
get in because we have foreign students
there. But I want to make sure that the
foreign students are people that can
love our country. We don't want to see
shopping centers exploding. We don't
want to see the kind of riots that you
had. And I'll tell you what, many of
those students didn't go anywhere. Many
of those students were troublemakers
caused by the radical left lunatics in
this country. All right, one more
question. President, go ahead, please.
Will will you pardon the people who are
accused of conspiring to kidnap Michigan
Governor Gretchian Whitmer? I'm going to
look at it. I will take a look at it. Uh
it's been brought to my attention. I did
watch the trial. It looked to me like
somewhat of a railroad job. I'll be
honest with you. It looked to me like
some people said some stupid things. You
know, they were drinking and I think
they said stupid things. But I'll take a
look at that. And uh a lot of people are
asking me that question from both sides.
Actually, a lot of people think uh they
got railroaded. A lot of people think
they got railroaded and probably some
people don't. No, one more. Go ahead.
How will the confrontation with Harvard
end? Do you you foresee? I don't know. I
don't I don't know. Harvard's got to
behave themselves. Harvard is treating
our country with great disrespect and
all they're doing is getting in deeper
and deeper and deeper. They've got to
behave themselves. You know, I'm looking
I'm looking out for the country and and
for Harvard. I want Harvard to do well.
I want Harvard to be great again
probably because how could it be great?
How could it be great when you have
Harvard announced two weeks ago that
they are going to teach remedial
mathematics? Remedial meaning they're
going to teach low-grade mathematics
like 2 + 2 is four. How did these people
get into Harvard if they can't if they
can't do basic
mathematics? How did they do it? I mean,
people with 1,600 on their boards don't
get in and they're getting they're
letting people in and they're bragging
about how they're teaching them basic
mathematics. Where did these people come
from? So, we have to look at the list
and and Harvard has to understand the
last thing I want to do is hurt them.
They're hurting themselves. They're
fighting. You know, Colombia has been uh
really they were very very bad what
they've done. very anti-Semitic and and
lots of other things, but they're
working with us on finding a solution.
And you know, they're taking off that
hot seat, but Harvard wants to fight.
They want to show how smart they are and
they're getting their ass kicked. Thank
you very much, everybody. Thank you.
Thank you guys.
Thanks, guys.
You are so great. Thank you. Thank you.
Good luck